Michael Abraham

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Extremely driven and creative software engineer graduate with an understanding and experience in the full software development lifecycle and OOP principles; received higher education which covered the development process of software architecture from concept to implementation and deployment. With this academic exposure, alongside various experiences as a sales advisor and a junior software engineer, Michael has gained a deep understanding for the importance of customer satisfaction and the production of quality deliverables.

Ambitious and versatile problem solver that gives maximum effort when learning new skills and encountering challenging obstacles.

Interests: Reading, Football, Gym & General Sports.

SKILLS

Personal Skills

- •High Intrinsic Motivation •Good Communicator •Dedicated •Quality Teamwork Skills
- •Confident Public Speaker •Innovative & Creative Thinker.

Key Skills

- Client Requirement Software Testing Web Apps Mobile Apps Scalable Applications
- •Clear & Relevant Documentation

Technical Skills

C#, C++, HTML, Git, CSS, Agile, TDD, Scrum (Advanced)

ASP.NET Web API, SQL, NUnit, Bootstrap, Python, Java, JavaScript, JQuery, Linux, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD (Intermediate)

Haskell, PHP, TypeScript (Beginner)

Education

August 2016

August 2020	BSc (Hons) Software Engineering:	Nottingham Trent University
	2:1	

- . .

Walton High, Milton Keynes

Sport Diploma (BTEC):

Michael Abraham

Science Subsidiary Diploma (BTEC):

D

August 2014 2 GCSE Level BTECs: D*

Walton High, Milton Keynes

1 GCSE Level BTEC: M

6 GCSEs: B-C (Includes English, Math & Science)

3 GCSEs: D

Employment History

[April 2015 - December 2019] [S

[Stock Control/ Dot Com/ Sales Advisor]

Tesco, Milton Keynes

[August 2014 – April 2015]

[Sales Advisor]

Debenhams, Milton Keynes

[June 2021 – Present]

[Junior Software Engineer]

Rascal Systems

Most Recent Academic Details (Software Engineering Modules, NTU)

Year One Computer Science Programming

- Completed the first-year modules using the languages Python and C++, learning the basics of both languages.
- An introduction to Microsoft Visual Studio was provided towards the latter terms of the academic year. This
 development environment was then consistently used throughout the remaining years of the course while later
 programming using C#, ASP.NET and JavaScript.

Year One Systems Analysis & Design with Professional Development

- During this module we completed group work, focused on delivering a Database Management Systems (DBMS) using Oracle with an agile approach. This concluded with a working DBMS application which utilized C# and Windows Forms, an extensive design documentation alongside the program, a group presentation, and a portfolio project to illustrate our personal capabilities.
- This module provided us with practice executing an agile approach to development and helped us to build on different group skills such as communication, team cohesion, adaptability. In a group led by me, formidable team management was required to distribute tasks that would highlight everyone's strengths and help develop their weaknesses to ultimately improve our groups productivity and meet our project goals.

Year Two Software Design and Implementation (SDI)/Software Engineering

- This part of the course involved learning the basics of Linux/Unix based systems and Minux. Throughout this academic year we were also taught a detailed understanding of C++ and the development of DBMS using Oracle.
- A web development module was taken that taught HTML (using ASP.net), CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript. For the completion of this module a responsive E-Commerce website was created, without the inclusion of Bootstrap, that delivered a variety of content over multiple pages and achieved a 2.1 grading.

Michael Abraham

When combining the software engineering and SDI modules taught during the 2nd academic year, skills to manufacture basic software structures and interfaces that are well programmed, documented and user friendly were grasped.

Final Year Advanced Software Engineering (ASE)

- The modules completed during the 3rd academic year trained the abilities to propose, design and evaluate advanced software architecture in groups and individually, with an intention that these skills can be transferred to working in real industries.
- A group project for a Stock Management System (SMS) was designed, implemented, and analyzed during the final year of the course. The system developed for Nottingham Trent University's on campus shops was designed in Balsamiq, then developed through C# and the GUI environment provided by Visual Studio. The SMS stored and organized shipment order details and the accompanying products in-store stock levels, also providing an Android mobile application to scan products details into the software program using QR codes. This well-structured project produced a portfolio that achieved a 2.1 after grading and moderating.
- An individual final year project was produced that designed, implemented, vigorously tested, and acutely documented the development of an independently prepared app. Through agile development the project produced an Android mobile application programmed in Java that integrated Firebase and Node.js for data storage and several functionalities. A 14k word report accompanied the project that illustrated the development process, the findings of testing and user testing and critically evaluated the outcomes of the project against its goals.
- During the ASE module functional programming through Haskell was introduced that taught the development
 of code through test driven development. Subsequently, a program alongside an evaluative documentation of
 the project was produced that achieved a grading of 2.1 for that task's deadline.

References

Kimberley Green	kgreen@mket.org.uk	
Sharon Alexander	salexander@mket.org.uk	07469713389
Peter FitzGerald	peter.fitzgerald@ntu.ac.uk	